<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portland Mortgage Video Blog with Joe Dimeo</title>
    <description>Our mission at Fairway Independent Mortgage Corp. is to be your best resource for Portland Mortgage advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about Mortgage. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Fairway Independent Mortgage Corp., your professional Portland Mortgage Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 10:46:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 10:46:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Make Your Offer Stand Out?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CuZxLZkRzGs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For homebuyers, one of the common questions we hear is, “How do I make my offer stand out?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your real estate agent is a good place to start.&lt;/strong&gt; You hired them for a reason, and that reason should be to get you the best property for the best price. If you need a referral, please let me know because I know some great agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I always suggest starting with the seller’s motivation.%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-make-your-offer-stand-out.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I always suggest starting with the seller’s motivation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my advice, I always suggest starting with the seller’s motivation. A handwritten letter makes you look desperate and overly emotional in my opinion. If you understand the seller’s motivation, you can craft your offer to fit their needs. &lt;strong&gt;You don’t have to come in with a high price, but you can offer a quick close or waive a contingency or two.&lt;/strong&gt; This will help everyone feel like they left the transaction a winner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you do need any recommendations for real estate agents or you have any questions regarding real estate or mortgages in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 11:12:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-make-your-offer-stand-out.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-make-your-offer-stand-out.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have Fun and Play With Pups at Our “Yappy” Hour Event</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ouTfhWh1Xsc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re invited to our upcoming “Yappy” Hour event! That’s right, bring your loved ones and your pups along for a great time at our office “700 SW 5th Avenue Portland, OR  97204” on August 15 at 4:30 p.m. It’s going to be a fantastic chance to mix and mingle, so we hope you’ll drop by to enjoy a free cocktail, get your furry friend a complimentary puppy pedicure, and chat with other local dog lovers. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to seeing you on August 15. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 22:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-fun-and-play-with-pups-at-our-yappy-hour-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/have-fun-and-play-with-pups-at-our-yappy-hour-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Know If It’s Time to Refinance</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P_eRnqW-U2w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask me whether it’s a good idea to refinance their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In answer, I ask them three questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has the market improved?&lt;/strong&gt; If the market in your area has gone up significantly over the last couple of years, meaning that money is actually cheaper, then you can absolutely refinance your home, potentially pull equity from it, and lower your payments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s no reason to pay more in interest than is necessary.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-if-its-time-to-refinance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s no reason to pay more in interest than is necessary.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you done substantial improvements to the home?&lt;/strong&gt; If, for example, you added some decks or really nice landscaping to your property, the value of your home will increase, potentially leading to a higher appraisal and loan-to-value ratio. Many good things can happen when it shows good ownership of a home and improvements in the value of the asset the bank has lent on because that’s ultimately what the banks are after. Someone who shows that they can make a home better after living in it and makes their payments on time is a less risky person to loan to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has your credit improved?&lt;/strong&gt; If you borrowed money when you had a credit score of 550 and you’re now at a 750, you represent less of a risk to the bank. There’s no reason to pay more in interest than is necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to stop wasting money on interest and find out what risk you represent to the bank? If so, then reach out to me. We can help you make sure that you’re not overpaying.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 14:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-if-its-time-to-refinance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-if-its-time-to-refinance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
